Well, it's so great to have everybody
here for this historic occasion
as the Toro District in Bridgeland. You
will get a sneak preview today. This is
an awesome state-of-the-art facility and
property cannot wait for it to get
started and be completed. I look out in
the crowd and I see so many of our
Texans family members, our friends, our
partners, Texans legends in the house,
former players of the Houston Texans.
So many media members here as well.
We're going to learn a lot about the
Toro District today. We also want to
recognize elected officials here in the
house or the tent. If you are an elected
official and members from your office,
please stand up and be recognized right
now.
Thank you for your service and
everything you do for the greater
Houston community. Afterwards, there
will be plenty of time for questions
from the media, photos, the backdrop
behind me. you can use that and that's
going to get very interesting in just a
few moments here. We are so excited
though and before we bring Cal and
Hannah McNair up here, we want to
recognize a person who if it weren't for
her efforts and for the efforts of the
late Bob McNair, we wouldn't be here
right now. This is the next generation
happening before our very eyes. maybe
the second biggest event in the history
of the franchise off field since the
launch of the Houston Texans October
6th, 1999. We are so privileged and
overjoyed to have in attendance with us
co-founder and the latest inductee into
the Houston Texans Ring of Honor. Won't
you please welcome Janice McNair.
And now, won't you please welcome chair
and CEO of the Houston Texans, Cal
McNair, and vice president of the
Houston Texans Foundation, Hannah
McNair. The McNairs.
I think I need another hand.
>> Uh, thank you, Mark, and thank you to
everyone for being here on this historic
day. We're thrilled to give you an
exclusive look at the Toro District, a
new 83 acre mixeduse sports and
entertainment destination that will be
built right here in Bridgeland.
To start off, we want to give a special
thanks to Howard Hughes, Commissioner
Bionis, and Commissioner Ramsay for
partnering with us on this project. We
feel very lucky to have partners who are
the best at what they do and understand
the magnitude of this project for both
us and the community.
>> We've been talking about wanting to
build a new headquarters and training
facility for years, and we're finally
here. Starting in 2029,
this will be the home of the Houston
Texans outside of game day and it's a
major development for the organization.
It will reshape the way we engage with
fans, youth, partners, and the greater
Houston community. It's the biggest move
our organization has made since our
inception.
We have talked about how our
organization is growing rapidly in a
number of different ways and we wanted
something worldclass to match where we
are headed. This will be an industry
tone setter for the global sports and
entertainment industry.
>> At the forefront of our decision- making
was a football team and how we can best
support our coaches and players. This
provides us with a competitive advantage
and puts them in an ideal situation
every day.
>> When Howard Hughes came to us with this
proposal, it was clear this is an
opportunity to build something iconic,
not just for our team, but for the
community in northwest Harris County and
greater Houston area. This further
emphasizes our goals of bringing a
championship to Houston, enhancing the
community, and making sports sports more
accessible to the community.
>> This project reinforces our long-term
commitment to Harris County and our
focus on driving growth, opportunity for
community. As you know, when my parents
brought football back to Houston, one of
their core pillars was to give back to
the community and make H-Town a better
place. This does that in a number of
different ways that we're excited to
share with y'all. Particularly for
particularly for the residents of
Bridgeland, Scyfare, Waller, and Lonear
College. As a Scyfare guy myself, it
means a lot to me personally to do this
right here.
>> We love Houston and this allows us to
open opportunities for both this area
commercially and economically. The new
headquarters and athletic complex will
provide expanded training facilities,
create new opportunities for youth
programming, community events, and
educational partnerships. The students
Cal was referring to will gain access to
internship career pathways and sports
focused educational initiatives
in an extremely unique way.
>> You're going to learn more about what
this historic project means throughout
the day. As you'll as you'll hear, we
want to make sure we are using the best
practices from around the world, but
also keeping things authentically Texan.
So, football and inspiring hope in the
community are at the forefront.
Now, the fun part. Now, I get to reveal
the official logo for the Toro District.
So, please direct your attention to the
TV screens throughout the tent. And
since I can't see them, you have to make
sure you tell me if you can see the
logo. Three, two, one.
>> These bulls might look familiar to you.
As you can see, the Toro district logo
is anchored by three Spanish fighting
bulls. These are inspired by the same
statues that are at the entrances to NRG
Park. Now connecting our 365 home here
with our game day home.
>> Again, thank you for being here. We're
excited. I hope y'all are excited. Right
now, we'll turn it back to Mark as we
proceed.
>> All right, how about it for Cal McNair
and Hannah McNair.
Thank you so much.
And please welcome to the podium now the
CEO of Howard Hughes Holdings, David
O'Reilly. David,
well, this event absolutely involves an
NFL team because every other time I've
been introduced, there's been nobody
clapping.
We're grateful that you're here and good
afternoon. Thank you for joining us.
Great moments are born from great
opportunity.
46 years ago, Coach Herb Brooks stood in
a locker room in Lake Placid and
inspired a group of kids
to believe they could do something
extraordinary.
On Sunday, we watched Team USA bring
home another goal, another reminder that
when preparation meets opportunity,
something powerful can happen.
Today, we're standing at the beginning
of one of those same moments
because Toro District is not just a
headquarters.
It's one of those great opportunities.
A great opportunity that will create
thousands of great moments for decades
to come. The opportunity for the
families of the 17,000 jobs that will be
created here. The opportunity for young
people to find career pathways and
apprenticeships that change the
trajectory of their lives. The
opportunity for a parent to bring their
child to see professional football up
close for the first time and maybe spark
a dream.
the opportunity for high school
students, high school championship teams
to compete in a venue where they have
incredible pride and the opportunity for
Northwest Harris County to grow, not by
accident, but by design.
Over the next 15 years, this district is
projected to generate 34 billion with a
B billion dollars in economic impact.
That number matters.
But what matters more are the moments
behind it. The first paycheck, the first
internship, the first time a community
gathers and feels connected.
At Howard Us, we believe that
communities are built over decades, not
development cycles. They're built with
patience, with discipline, and with
partners who are willing to take a
longterm view.
This partnership between the Houston
Texans, Harris County, and Howard Hughes
reflects that mindset. It reflects
confidence. It reflects leadership. And
it reflects a shared belief that this
region deserves intentional growth.
Northwest Harris County is one of the
fastest growing courses in Texas and
fastest growing areas in the country.
Growth is coming.
The question is whether we shape it or
we let it shape us.
Toro district is about choosing to shape
it. It's about aligning infrastructure,
opportunity, and leadership so that
growth strengthens this region, not
strains it.
I want to thank Cal and Hannah McNair
for their vision and their deep
commitment to Houston. And Mike Tolman,
I can't think of a better brother to be
a war with, man. It's been awesome.
The Texans aren't just building a
headquarters. They're not just building
a building. They're planting a long-term
flag right here in Bridgeland,
reinforcing their commitment to this
region. And at the end of the day, they
are going to write the next chapter of
Houston's history.
I want to thank our commissioners,
Brionis and Ramsey.
I can tell you that every step of the
way throughout working on this,
they ensured that this project delivers
real benefits for the residents they
serve.
And of course, I need to thank all my
employees, my fellow employees, my
partners at Howard Hughes who worked
tirelessly to help bring this day to
fruition.
Great moments are born from great
opportunity.
Today, we are creating that opportunity
together.
And I have no doubt that the moments
that will be born here for families, for
businesses, for athletes, and for this
community will define this region for
generations.
We are proud to build what comes next.
Thank you,
David O'Reilly.
How about David channeling the miracle
speech? Very nice. It's very nice
indeed. Okay, joining us now, please
welcome Harris County Commissioner
Precinct for Leslie Bionis.
>> Good afternoon everyone. How proud are
you to be here today sitting here as a
proud Texan?
This is a great day in Harris County and
a great day to be a Houston Texans fan
and to be a Texan. I first want to thank
our unbelievable partners. Can we give
it up one more time for the McNair
family
and to Mike Tomen, our president of the
Houston Texans and my brother and how do
we get to yes
and to Juan and all the amazing Houston
Texans leaders and to our players both
current, past and future. Can we give it
up one more time?
And to David O'Reilly and all of the
Howard Hughes team, thank you for
building community. Thank you for what
you do and for your partnership.
And to my partner, my colleague, and my
neighbor, Harris County Commissioner,
Precinct 3, Commissioner Tom Ramsay.
Thank you, Commissioner Ramsey.
to you and to your precinct 3 team,
especially Eric Hepin. And to my Harris
County Precinct 4 team, could you please
along with all the other Harris County
team members just stand for a second?
You are true public servants that serve
with heart, hustle, and higher
standards. Jesse, John, come on. Dan,
Daniel,
this is the solutionsoriented government
that our community deserves. and for
everything our constable Terry
Albrittain, Constable Precinct 5, and
Constable Precinct 4 Mark Herman that
y'all do to keep us safe. Can we give it
up for them and all of our law
enforcement partners?
And we have Harris County Sheriff's
officers as well as our Sheriff
Gonzalez. So, thank you for keeping us
safe. The reason Harris County is so
proud to be a partner in this
transformational public private
partnership that I believe will be a
model for the country is this really is
one of those winwinwins that we're
always searching for. This is a win for
Harris County. If you have heard Harris
County is one of the fastest growing
areas of the country. Harris County
generally will grow 40% over the next 25
years. But in this area, it's expected
to grow by over 300%.
This is the future center of gravity for
Harris County and it will be catalyzed
by this landmark transformational public
private partnership. This 83 acre area
will be what catalyzes this area even
further. This is a win for economic
opportunity. the $34 billion in economic
growth for our region. This district
alone will create over 17,000
jobs. This is a win for creating jobs.
And those jobs with public funds, they
will meet our Harris County minimum wage
policy for the contractor of 21.65 an
hour. They will comply with our work
site safety policy so that one job here
in Harris County is enough and that you
can go home safely to your families.
This is a win for education. And as a
former teacher and as the daughter of
former educators of 50 years, I look at
my Scyfare ISD partners. Can we raise
your hands one more time? Thank you. And
our Waller ISD partners and our Lonear
College partners.
This is a win for our students. The
internships, the apprenticeshipships,
the speaker series for the community
colleges, access to the sports fields,
Friday night lights, access for
graduations.
This will be a center and a win for the
educational opportunity. And this is
also a win for safe infrastructure,
which is what Harris County works on all
day, every day. We will, as a result of
this public private partnership, get
four new community parks, additional
green space. We will have more
accelerated investment in key corridors
in this area, new roads, bridges,
drainage right here on the corridor of
99 and 290. Sidewalks, trails for safe
connection will be accelerated because
of this project. And this is also a win
for good government. For all of you who
have spent hours in your car going
downtown to get a marriage license,
transfer vehicle titles, to pay taxes,
well, guess what? Part of this amazing
deal, Harris County will be bringing
government services right here into the
heart of Northwest Harris County with a
services hub, community center, and
various government services from law
enforcement, clerk's office, tax
assessor office, and beyond. So this
will be a win for educational
opportunity, economic opportunity, for
good government and also for the quality
of life. Think about the memories in
addition to today that we will create
here together. And I was talking
to Mike and to Mrs. McNair that one day
when we are at the Super Bowl and we win
the Super Bowl, so many fans will be
cheering them on from the amazing fan
experience that will be right here. So
this is
this is one of those win-winwins
and that's what we're always searching
for when the power of government and
private industry can come together to do
meaningful big things and as a proud
native Texan that's what we do here. We
do big bold hard things and we get it
done and this is going to transform and
be a model for the rest of the country.
So I'm going to do a very brief version
I was asked to do in Spanish.
Houston,
Howard Hughes,
Tom,
Victoria,
Houston Texans Howard Hughes
Harris
Katriento
district
central
Victoria,
the
educos.
Victoria,
grandch
Toro district.
Houston
Harris.
We are keeping our beloved Houston
Texans here at home in Harris County.
So, we look forward to many more decades
of finding these win-win wins as a
community because again, as
Houstononians, as Harris County
residents, and as proud Houston Texans,
that is what we do here. So with that,
one more time, let us celebrate this
amazing public private partnership.
>> How about it, Leslie Bionis?
Now, won't you please welcome Harris
County Commissioner from Precinct 3, Tom
Ramsey.
>> What a what a great day in Harris
County. I mean, I've been a football fan
as long as I can remember. This is a
center of football in our universe. It's
only natural that we should have the
best facilities, the best football team
on the planet, which we do. Want to
thank the McNairs for your leadership
through the years. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Howard Hughes, it can't can't
go beyond words in terms of what y'all
bring to this uh equation. Makes a
difference. And you said it earlier,
partnership. and Mike Tolman, thank you
for leading us through the uh messy
details of putting all this thing
together. And I look out here and I I
want to go get half of your autograph,
the legends out here. I did say uh I did
see Dan Pastor Rainey earlier, even
though he wasn't a Texan. I think he
wanted to be, but we have such a rich
history of sports in this county. It's
it's just amazing that we're able to put
something like this together. Look
forward to what this will be. Harris
County is the third largest county in
America.
Not in Texas, in America. We deserve the
very best. I grew up in East Texas and
we need something that I would call
bodacious.
And this is a first step in what I would
think bodacious should look like. So,
anybody that wants to do halfbaked
uh duct tape and bailing wire, I'm not
interested. What we need to do is
something that makes a statement and
gets out here and sets a tone. I think
that sends a message to our football
players. I think that sends a message to
the future volleyball players that we're
going to be having out here as well. I'm
a licensed professional engineer. I
guess I'll have to apologize for that.
Sometimes I get stuck in the weeds. But
there's nothing nothing more encouraging
to me than a plan.
So much of the development that happens
around us is unplanned. It's we're
responding. I see my text dot friends
here and the district engineers here. Uh
a lot of times text has to go build the
freeway after the people move there. But
we're trying to get ahead of the curve
just a bit. We're trying to get the
facilities built just ahead of when
they're coming. This is a full
legitimate partnership. The Texans are
contributing a significant amount to
this partnership. The Howard Hughes
Group is contributing a significant
amount to this group and we're just
happy that we can come through as the
county and contribute on the
infrastructure. That's what we're going
to be doing anyway. And you know, when
we're going to be doing it anyway, why
don't we do it up front? Why don't we
get out in front of things rather than
always about 10 years late? There's
going to be the Mason Road bridge built
because of this. There's going to be the
Peak Road Bridge because of this. I know
people that live in this area, they want
to get from point A to point B. This
project will facilitate our ability to
get from point A to point B. So, it is a
effective, wonderful plan that I think
uses the tools that we should be using.
I've been to most of the 254 counties
that are in Texas. All of them have a
county courthouse. All of them have the
center of what is the business district.
This is what this is. This is our county
courthouse. This is our center of doing
business in Harris County, at least in
the northwest portion. So, I'm excited
that the 25,000 foot facility will offer
the county services that Mr. Bionis
referenced earlier. Uh, we've needed a
town center. Uh, as I've told my Cypress
friends, we've been looking for Cyprus
for the last 20 years. Well, we're about
to find it. We're about to create a
center where we can say, you know, I
know where the center of Cyprus is and
where we can go. I think this is a
perfect example of what partnerships
should be about. This is a perfect
example of planning. It's been a real
pleasure to partner with Commissioner
Bionis. I hope y'all hadn't missed that.
There are partnerships that matter. This
is an effective partnership, I think,
from precinct 4 and precinct 3. I know
what y'all see on TV. You see a bunch of
fussing and fighting and how we can't
get things done. Yes, we can. This is an
example of when we put our minds to it,
I see our county attorney over there and
others. When we put our heads together,
I think we can make it happen. Thank
y'all for what y'all do as a community.
I see a lot of friends out there and
then and y'all are celebrating, too.
Sure, there's a lot of questions.
There's a still a lot of details that
we're working out, but I can tell you we
have a framework and I'm excited to be a
Houston Texan fan today. Thank you.
Tom Ramsey, everybody.
And now with more on this amazing
project, the president of the Houston
Texans, Mike Tolman.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. What
what an incredible day we've already
had, especially to be standing here on
the future site of the Toro District and
think about the impact it will have in
the near future and the long term.
We couldn't be more excited to bring a
worldclass project to bear. as Cal said
earlier that we'll be authentically
Texans and we'll be authentically
Houston. Now, I want to double click on
the process a little bit uh that's been
mentioned. We've had some guiding
principles that have taken us through
this process.
We have a purpose. We call it our
charge. And our purpose is to win
championships, cultivate a world-class
fan experience, and inspire hope in
Houston. That has been a guiding
principle when we've been looking for
our new home. Now, on a practical level,
we've been looking for that competitive
advantage, the competitive advantage for
our football team and for us as Houston
Texans to all be together in one space.
You've heard a lot about the community.
I think you've heard about that because
that is something that aligns all of us.
The community impact is important to us.
And through that lens, making sports
accessible to the youth and the public
at large is also very important, an
important driver as we looked for our
new home. Now, in conversations with
Howard Hughes, we started to realize
that that could be our partner on that
front. We could not be more excited
about. Howard Hughes is a worldclass
respected
developer of large-scale communities,
most respected in the United States. And
it was under David's leadership with the
whole team
that we could see this all come
together. Another piece that was really
important that the McNairs emphasized,
Harris County is important to us. The
ability to be here in northwest Harris
County and call this our home was a key
driver.
So, I want to thank our county partners
for helping us get there.
I want to thank the commissioner's court
for the unanimous support.
I also please
And I want a special thanks to
Commissioner Leslie Brionis and
Commissioner Tom Ramsey for their
amazing leadership throughout the entire
process,
keeping residents first and keeping the
community at the top of the
conversation.
As Cal said, this is our biggest move
since our inception.
And so as we look to the future, I want
to share some details.
Our headquarters
based here anchoring the district will
be 175,000 square feet. It will be the
home for our football operations and
business operations together.
As we've said, football is the focus. It
is the main thing for us when we were
driving here to make sure we had a
competitive advantage for the team.
So, this headquarters will showcase
state-of-the-art,
training room, weight room, recovery
room, performance center, health and
wellness, nutrition,
meeting space, coaches offices. so our
players can get through their day
without friction focused in on the goal.
There will also be three outdoor NFLsiz
football fields. We'll have multiple
flag football fields outside as well.
This campus will also be anchored by our
fieldhouse
which will host our indoor practice
facility, our indoor football field.
would be 150,000 square feet. Now, this
fieldhouse can also support three indoor
flag football fields and up to 21
volleyball courts.
Has a capacity up to 16,000 people. So
we can host a multiple
different type of events from
graduations
to NFL style, NFL scale events.
And as Commissioner Ramsey said, also a
hub for our corporate community. We can
host private events there for businesses
to conduct their business and showcase
this region.
So, as we stand here today,
we could not be more excited to make
this a 365 day a year destination for
our partners, for our fans, and families
alike.
A place to truly live, work, and play
together in the community. Now, since
this is a true partnership, I'm going to
ask well, I'm going to ask Toro to come
out. Um, and I'm going to ask our
partners to join me in sharing the first
renderings of the Toro district. The
McNairs,
David O'Reilly, Commissioner Brionis,
and Commissioner Ramsey. Please come on
up. Where's Toro?
Here he comes.
We have construction Toro with us
appropriately and he's bringing out the
battle red button.
Everybody's going to get in position to
press the button for a big moment here
at the Toro District.
Everybody ready?
Everybody's ready.
3 2 1 go Texans.
Outstanding.
As everybody gets their photos, we'll
have a chance for the media to catch up
with our partners and Texans officials
here today. You're all going to look at
the images here of the Toro district
with the new logo. Thank you so much for
being here and as always, go Texans.